ielts-mentor.com 2018-07-13

# Privacy Policy

##  Privacy Policy 

Details
     Last Updated: Sunday, 01 July 2018 15:39 
     Written by IELTS Mentor 
     Hits: 8812 

##  IELTS Mentor Privacy Policy

Effective date: July 01, 2018.

IELTS Mentor operates the https://www.ielts-mentor.com website (also termed as 'Service').

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our website and or application and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. You can access disclaimer page from our <https://www.ielts-mentor.com/disclaimer> page

##  Information Collection And Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

###  Types of Data Collected

####  Personal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Email address
  * First name and last name
  * Phone number
  * Address, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, City
  * Cookies and Usage Data

####  Usage Data

We may also collect information how the Service is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

####  Tracking & Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

  * **Session Cookies.** We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
  * **Preference Cookies.** We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
  * **Security Cookies.** We use Security Cookies for security purposes.

For more about our Cookie Policy please visit <https://www.ielts-mentor.com/cookie-policy>

##  Use of Data

IELTS Mentor uses the collected data for various purposes:

  * To provide and maintain the Service
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
  * To provide customer care and support
  * To provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the Service
  * To monitor the usage of the Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues

##  Transfer Of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be stored to our server and maintained on computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

IELTS Mentor will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

##  Disclosure Of Data

###  Legal Requirements

IELTS Mentor may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  * To comply with a legal obligation
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of IELTS Mentor
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
  * To protect against legal liability

##  Security Of Data

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

##  Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

###  Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

  * **Google Analytics**

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

##  Our Commitment to Privacy:

Your privacy is important to us. We do not, under any circumstances, directly collect your personal information, share it with others, nor use it for any marketing or promotional offer. If you comment on a post, your email is kept hidden from public visibility. You can anytime reach to us and ask for the removal of any comment you have made.

If your information regarding finding a speaking partner is published on our website, we remove them after your exam date is over or upon a request from you anytime. Our commitment to your privacy and personal data is our first priority.

##  Commenting and Subscription:

Any messages you send us via the email address is never disclosed to anyone else other than our team member. If you explicitly request us to publish your details so that other test takers can find you to practice online, we do so and remove it after a certain period of time. You have full control over removing such comments or messages.

If you subscribe to our website using your email address, we sporadically send you update notifications. We do not use a subscriber's information to personally reach him/her or for any other purposes other than sending notification about content updates. You have full control over your subscription. You can unsubscribe from our website anytime you want.

##  Links To Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

##  Children's Privacy

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 ("Children").

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

##  Changes To This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the "effective date" at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

##  Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

  * By email: [info@ielts-mentor.com](mailto:info@ielts-mentor.com)
  * By visiting this page on our website: https://www.ielts-mentor.com/contact-us
